[
    {
        "question": "How many times \"NepalBIX\" is get printed?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int x;\r\n    for(x=-1; x<=10; x++)\r\n    {\r\n        if(x < 5)\r\n            continue;\r\n        else\r\n            break;\r\n        printf(\"NepalBIX\");\r\n    }\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Infinite times",
        "b": "11 times",
        "c": "0 times",
        "d": "10 times",
        "answer": "0 times"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times the while loop will get executed if a short int is 2 byte wide?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int j=1;\r\n    while(j <= 255)\r\n    {\r\n        printf(\"%c %d\\n\", j, j);\r\n        j++;\r\n    }\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Infinite times",
        "b": "255 times",
        "c": "256 times",
        "d": "254 times",
        "answer": "255 times"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not logical operator?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "&",
        "b": "&&",
        "c": "||",
        "d": "!",
        "answer": "&"
    },
    {
        "question": "In mathematics and computer programming, which is the correct order of mathematical operators ?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Addition, Subtraction, Multiplication, Division",
        "b": "Division, Multiplication, Addition, Subtraction",
        "c": "Multiplication, Addition, Division, Subtraction",
        "d": "Addition, Division, Modulus, Subtraction",
        "answer": "Division, Multiplication, Addition, Subtraction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cannot be checked in a switch-case statement?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Character",
        "b": "Integer",
        "c": "Float",
        "d": "enum",
        "answer": "Float"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i=0;\r\n    for(; i<=5; i++);\r\n        printf(\"%d\", i);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5",
        "b": "5",
        "c": "1, 2, 3, 4",
        "d": "6",
        "answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    char str[]=\"C-program\";\r\n    int a = 5;\r\n    printf(a >10?\"Ps\\n\":\"%s\\n\", str);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "C-program",
        "b": "Ps",
        "c": "Error",
        "d": "None of above",
        "answer": "C-program"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int a = 500, b = 100, c;\r\n    if(!a >= 400)\r\n        b = 300;\r\n    c = 200;\r\n    printf(\"b = %d c = %d\\n\", b, c);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "b = 300 c = 200",
        "b": "b = 100 c = garbage",
        "c": "b = 300 c = garbage",
        "d": "b = 100 c = 200",
        "answer": "b = 100 c = 200"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    unsigned int i = 65535; \/* Assume 2 byte integer*\/\r\n    while(i++ != 0)\r\n        printf(\"%d\",++i);\r\n    printf(\"\\n\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Infinite loop",
        "b": "0 1 2 ... 65535",
        "c": "0 1 2 ... 32767 - 32766 -32765 -1 0",
        "d": "No output",
        "answer": "Infinite loop"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int x = 3;\r\n    float y = 3.0;\r\n    if(x == y)\r\n        printf(\"x and y are equal\");\r\n    else\r\n        printf(\"x and y are not equal\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "x and y are equal",
        "b": "x and y are not equal",
        "c": "Unpredictable",
        "d": "No output",
        "answer": "x and y are equal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program, if a short int is 2 bytes wide?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    short int i = 0;\r\n    for(i<=5 && i>=-1; ++i; i>0)\r\n        printf(\"%u,\", i);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "1 ... 65535",
        "b": "Expression syntax error",
        "c": "No output",
        "d": "0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5",
        "answer": "1 ... 65535"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    char ch;\r\n    if(ch = printf(\"\"))\r\n        printf(\"It matters\\n\");\r\n    else\r\n        printf(\"It doesn't matters\\n\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "It matters",
        "b": "It doesn't matters",
        "c": "matters",
        "d": "No output",
        "answer": "It doesn't matters"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    unsigned int i = 65536; \/* Assume 2 byte integer*\/\r\n    while(i != 0)\r\n        printf(\"%d\",++i);\r\n    printf(\"\\n\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Infinite loop",
        "b": "0 1 2 ... 65535",
        "c": "0 1 2 ... 32767 - 32766 -32765 -1 0",
        "d": "No output",
        "answer": "No output"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    float a = 0.7;\r\n    if(0.7 > a)\r\n        printf(\"Hi\\n\");\r\n    else\r\n        printf(\"Hello\\n\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Hi",
        "b": "Hello",
        "c": "Hi Hello",
        "d": "None of above",
        "answer": "Hi"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int a=0, b=1, c=3;\r\n    *((a) ? &b : &a) = a ? b : c;\r\n    printf(\"%d, %d, %d\\n\", a, b, c);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "0, 1, 3",
        "b": "1, 2, 3",
        "c": "3, 1, 3",
        "d": "1, 3, 1",
        "answer": "3, 1, 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int k, num = 30;\r\n    k = (num < 10) ? 100 : 200;\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", num);\r\n    re",
        "a": "200",
        "b": "30",
        "c": "100",
        "d": "500",
        "answer": "30"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int a = 300, b, c;\r\n    if(a >= 400)\r\n        b = 300;\r\n    c = 200;\r\n    printf(\"%d, %d, %d\\n\", a, b, c);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "300, 300, 200",
        "b": "Garbage, 300, 200",
        "c": "300, Garbage, 200",
        "d": "300, 300, Garbage",
        "answer": "300, Garbage, 200"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i=3;\r\n    switch(i)\r\n    {\r\n        case 1:\r\n            printf(\"Hello\\n\");\r\n        case 2:\r\n            printf(\"Hi\\n\");\r\n        case 3:\r\n            continue;\r\n        default:\r\n            printf(\"Bye\\n\");\r\n    }\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: Misplaced continue",
        "b": "Bye",
        "c": "No output",
        "d": "Hello Hi",
        "answer": "Error: Misplaced continue"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int x = 10, y = 20;\r\n    if(!(!x) && x)\r\n        printf(\"x = %d\\n\", x);\r\n    else\r\n        printf(\"y = %d\\n\", y);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "y =20",
        "b": "x = 0",
        "c": "x = 10",
        "d": "x = 1",
        "answer": "x = 10"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i=4;\r\n    switch(i)\r\n    {\r\n        default:\r\n           printf(\"This is default\\n\");\r\n        case 1:\r\n           printf(\"This is case 1\\n\");\r\n           break;\r\n        case 2:\r\n           printf(\"This is case 2\\n\");\r\n           break;\r\n        case 3:\r\n           printf(\"This is case 3\\n\");\r\n    }\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "This is default This is case 1",
        "b": "This is case 3 This is default",
        "c": "This is case 1 This is case 3",
        "d": "This is default",
        "answer": "This is default This is case 1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i = 1;\r\n    switch(i)\r\n    {\r\n        printf(\"Hello\\n\");\r\n        case 1:\r\n            printf(\"Hi\\n\");\r\n            break;\r\n        case 2:\r\n            printf(\"\\nBye\\n\");\r\n            break;\r\n    }\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Hello Hi",
        "b": "Hello Bye",
        "c": "Hi",
        "d": "Bye",
        "answer": "Hi"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    char j=1;\r\n    while(j < 5)\r\n    {\r\n        printf(\"%d, \", j);\r\n        j = j+1;\r\n    }\r\n    printf(\"\\n\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "1 2 3 ... 127",
        "b": "1 2 3 ... 255",
        "c": "1 2 3 ... 127 128 0 1 2 3 ... infinite times",
        "d": "1, 2, 3, 4",
        "answer": "1, 2, 3, 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int x, y, z;\r\n    x=y=z=1;\r\n    z = ++x || ++y && ++z;\r\n    printf(\"x=%d, y=%d, z=%d\\n\", x, y, z);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "x=2, y=1, z=1",
        "b": "x=2, y=2, z=1",
        "c": "x=2, y=2, z=2",
        "d": "x=1, y=2, z=1",
        "answer": "x=2, y=1, z=1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error, if any in the for loop.\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i=1;\r\n    for(;;)\r\n    {\r\n        printf(\"%d\\n\", i++);\r\n        if(i>10)\r\n           break;\r\n    }\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "There should be a condition in the for loop",
        "b": "The two semicolons should be dropped",
        "c": "The for loop should be replaced with while loop.",
        "d": "No error",
        "answer": "No error"
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error, if any in the program.\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int a = 10;\r\n    switch(a)\r\n    {\r\n    }\r\n    printf(\"This is c program.\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: No case statement specified",
        "b": "Error: No default specified",
        "c": "No Error",
        "d": "Error: infinite loop occurs",
        "answer": "No Error"
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error, if any in the program.\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i = 1;\r\n    switch(i)\r\n    {\r\n        printf(\"This is c program.\");\r\n        case 1:\r\n            printf(\"Case1\");\r\n            break;\r\n        case 2:\r\n            printf(\"Case2\");\r\n            break;\r\n    }\r\nreturn 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: No default specified",
        "b": "Error: Invalid printf statement after switch statement",
        "c": "No Error and prints \"Case1\"",
        "d": "None of above",
        "answer": "No Error and prints \"Case1\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error, if any in the while loop.\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i=1;\r\n    while()\r\n    {\r\n        printf(\"%d\\n\", i++);\r\n        if(i>10)\r\n           break;\r\n    }\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "There should be a condition in the while loop",
        "b": "There should be at least a semicolon in the while",
        "c": "The while loop should be replaced with for loop.",
        "d": "No error",
        "answer": "There should be a condition in the while loop"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following errors would be reported by the compiler on compiling the program given below?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int a = 5;\r\n    switch(a)\r\n    {\r\n    case 1:\r\n    printf(\"First\");\r\n    case 2:\r\n    printf(\"Second\");\r\n    case 3 + 2:\r\n    printf(\"Third\");\r\n    case 5:\r\n    printf(\"Final\");\r\n    break;\r\n    }\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "There is no break statement in each case.",
        "b": "Expression as in case 3 + 2 is not allowed.",
        "c": "Duplicate case case 5:",
        "d": "No error will be reported.",
        "answer": "Duplicate case case 5:"
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error, if any in the program.\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int P = 10;\r\n    switch(P)\r\n    {\r\n       case 10:\r\n       printf(\"Case 1\");\r\n       case 20:\r\n       printf(\"Case 2\");\r\n       break;\r\n       case P:\r\n       printf(\"Case 2\");\r\n       break;\r\n    }\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: No default value is specified",
        "b": "Error: Constant expression required at line case P:",
        "c": "Error: There is no break statement in each case.",
        "d": "No error will be reported.",
        "answer": "Error: Constant expression required at line case P:"
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error, if any in the program.\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i = 1;\r\n    switch(i)\r\n    {\r\n        case 1:\r\n           printf(\"Case1\");\r\n           break;\r\n        case 1*2+4:\r\n           printf(\"Case2\");\r\n           break;\r\n    }\r\nreturn 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: in case 1*2+4 statement",
        "b": "Error: No default specified",
        "c": "Error: in switch statement",
        "d": "No Error",
        "answer": "No Error"
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error, if any in the while loop.\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    void fun();\r\n    int i = 1;\r\n    while(i <= 5)\r\n    {\r\n        printf(\"%d\\n\", i);\r\n        if(i>2)\r\n            goto here;\r\n    }\r\nreturn 0;\r\n}\r\nvoid fun()\r\n{\r\n    here:\r\n    printf(\"It works\");\r\n}",
        "a": "No Error: prints \"It works\"",
        "b": "Error: fun() cannot be accessed",
        "c": "Error: goto cannot takeover control to other function",
        "d": "No error",
        "answer": "Error: goto cannot takeover control to other function"
    },
    {
        "question": "Point out the error, if any in the program.\r\n#include<stdio.h> \r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int a = 10, b;\r\n    a >=5 ? b=100: b=200;\r\n    printf(\"%d\\n\", b);\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "100",
        "b": "200",
        "c": "Error: L value required for b",
        "d": "Garbage value",
        "answer": "Error: L value required for b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements are correct about the below program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i = 10, j = 20;\r\n    if(i = 5) && if(j = 10)\r\n        printf(\"Have a nice day\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Output: Have a nice day",
        "b": "No output",
        "c": "Error: Expression syntax",
        "d": "Error: Undeclared identifier if",
        "answer": "Error: Expression syntax"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements are correct about the below program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i = 10, j = 15;\r\n    if(i % 2 = j % 3)\r\n        printf(\"NepalBIX\\n\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: Expression syntax",
        "b": "Error: Lvalue required",
        "c": "Error: Rvalue required",
        "d": "The Code runs successfully",
        "answer": "Error: Lvalue required"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements are correct about the program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int x = 30, y = 40;\r\n    if(x == y)\r\n        printf(\"x is equal to y\\n\");\r\n    else if(x > y)\r\n        printf(\"x is greater than y\\n\");\r\n    else if(x < y)\r\n        printf(\"x is less than y\\n\")\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: Statement missing",
        "b": "Error: Expression syntax",
        "c": "Error: Lvalue required",
        "d": "Error: Rvalue required",
        "answer": "Error: Statement missing"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements are correct about an if-else statements in a C-program?\r\n1:\tEvery if-else statement can be replaced by an equivalent statements using   ?: operators\r\n2:\tNested if-else statements are allowed.\r\n3:\tMultiple statements in an if block are allowed.\r\n4:\tMultiple statements in an else block are allowed.",
        "a": "1 and 2",
        "b": "2 and 3",
        "c": "1, 2 and 4",
        "d": "2, 3, 4",
        "answer": "2, 3, 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements are correct about the below program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int i = 0;\r\n    i++;\r\n    if(i <= 5)\r\n    {\r\n        printf(\"NepalBIX\\n\");\r\n        exit(0);\r\n        main();\r\n    }\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "The program prints 'NepalBIX' 5 times",
        "b": "The program prints 'NepalBIX' one time",
        "c": "The call to main() after exit() doesn't materialize.",
        "d": "The compiler reports an error since main() cannot call itself.",
        "answer": "The program prints 'NepalBIX' one time"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following sentences are correct about a for loop in a C program?\r\n1:\tfor loop works faster than a while loop.\r\n2:\tAll things that can be done using a for loop can also be done using a while loop.\r\n3:\tfor(;;); implements an infinite loop.\r\n4:\tfor loop can be used if we want statements in a loop get executed at least once.",
        "a": "1",
        "b": "1, 2",
        "c": "2, 3",
        "d": "2, 3, 4",
        "answer": "2, 3, 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements are correct about the below program?\r\n#include<stdio.h>\r\nint main()\r\n{\r\n    int n = 0, y = 1;\r\n    y == 1 ? n=0 : n=1;\r\n    if(n)\r\n        printf(\"Yes\\n\");\r\n    else\r\n        printf(\"No\\n\");\r\n    return 0;\r\n}",
        "a": "Error: Declaration terminated incorrectly",
        "b": "Error: Syntax error",
        "c": "Error: Lvalue required",
        "d": "None of above",
        "answer": "Error: Lvalue required"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following sentences are correct about a switch loop in a C program?\r\n1:\tswitch is useful when we wish to check the value of variable against a particular set of values.\r\n2:\tswitch is useful when we wish to check whether a value falls in different ranges.\r\n3:\tCompiler implements a jump table for cases used in switch.\r\n4:\tIt is not necessary to use a break in every switch statement.",
        "a": "1,2",
        "b": "1,3,4",
        "c": "2,4",
        "d": "2",
        "answer": "1,3,4"
    },
    {
        "question": "A short integer is at least 16 bits wide and a long integer is at least 32 bits wide.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "If scanf() is used to store a value in a char variable then along with the value a carriage return(\\r) also gets stored it.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The modulus operator cannot be used with a long double.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "A char variable can store either an ASCII character or a Unicode character.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "The way the break is used to take control out of switch and continue to take control of the beginning of the switch?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "No"
    },
    {
        "question": "Can we use a switch statement to switch on strings?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "No"
    },
    {
        "question": "We want to test whether a value lies in the range 2 to 4 or 5 to 7. Can we do this using a switch?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "Yes"
    },
    {
        "question": "By default, the data type of a constant without a decimal point is int, whereas the one with a decimal point is a double.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "Yes"
    }
]